2  1  6  4  2  0
Two one six four two zero
1  9  8  9
one nine eight nine.
妹子  这就是π小数点后一千位数
And that, little lady, is pi to a thousand places.
如果我问了你  那我愿意道歉
I'd say I'm sorry I asked,
可我连问都没问
except I didn't.
这是刊登了我跟莱纳德
Oh, look, it's the Scientific American
合写论文的科普杂志《科学美国人》
that covered the paper Leonard and I wrote.
给我看看
Oh, let me see.
其实当时面谈我情绪挺复杂
I have mixed feelings about doing interviews.
我享受我滔滔不绝的时刻
I like the part where I talk.
但我讨厌对方说话  我得听的时刻
I do not like the part where the other man talks.
谢尔顿  这篇文章完全没提到莱纳德
Sheldon, this article doesn't mention Leonard at all.
怎么可能
Well, that can't be right.
里面只写了"库珀博士与其团队"
It only refers to "Dr. Cooper and his team."
你中间有提过他吗
Did you even talk about him?
我就回答了几个跟我们理论有关的问题
All I did was answer a few questions about the theory.
然后表达了我对《科学美国人》杂志中
And then expressed my gratitude that Scientific American
并不会附上难闻香水卡片的感激之意
doesn't include any of those smelly perfume cards.
莱纳德真可怜
Poor Leonard.
哪里可怜了  他想出来的理论
Why? The theory he came up with
被《科学美国人》刊登了呢
just got mentioned in Scientific American.
他应该会爽到飞起来
He ought to be thrilled.
他很可能不会太爽
He might not be.
可能你说的对
Oh, maybe you're right.
他这人挺傻的
He is kind of a lump.
你想想嘛
Think about it.
如果哪天你被人一笔带过  仅被称为
How would you feel if you were referred to
"莱纳德博士团队中的一员"
as part of Leonard's team?
我会怒火烧尽九重天
Oh, I'd be incensed.
那你现在懂我想表达的意思了吗
So you see what I'm getting at?
"会哭的孩子有糖吃"吗
Squeaky wheel gets the grease?
不是
No.
"这山望着那山高"吗
Grass is always greener?
再想想
Try again.
我不知道啦  我们全都是格鲁特吗
Well, I don't know-- we're all Groot?
你就直说吧
Just tell me.
你们俩对这篇论文做出了同等的贡献
Leonard is as much a part of this paper as you are,
而他却被人忽略了
and he was overlooked.
他会不开心的
He's going to feel bad.
但这又不是我的错
But it wasn't my fault.
我又没故意不提他
I didn't exclude him.
而且这篇报导也不是我写的
And I didn't write the article.
还记得你在迪士尼乐园时
Remember that time you didn't get picked to
他们没选你而是选了另一个孩子
pull the sword out of the stone at Disneyland
去拔出石中剑吗
and they let that other kid do it?
那个死孩子
Oh, that kid!
可怜的莱纳德
Poor Leonard.
就是啊
Exactly.
不得不说  选那孩子真是个烂决定
For the record, that kid was a terrible choice.
如果你糖油条掉地上就会哭
If you cry when you drop your churro,
你绝对没那个本事去统治英国[亚瑟王]
you do not have what it takes to rule England.
谢谢你帮忙整理我妈的遗物
Thanks for helping us sort through all my mom's stuff.
应该的
Of course.
我明白那种
I know what it's like
整理亲爱的人的遗物的感觉
having to go through a loved one's possessions.
我叔叔曾是黑天神的崇拜者
My uncle was a worshipper of Krishna.
但在他死后  你猜我们发现了什么
But after he died, you know what we found?
一尊湿婆的雕像
A statue of Shiva.
虽然比不上咸党大战甜党
It may not be Crips and Bloods, okay?
但在印度  这也不是小事好吗
But in India, it's a thing.
你在场也挺好的
Well, it'll be good that you're there.
霍华德对于判断
Howard's been having trouble deciding
物件的取舍还挺费劲的
what to keep and what to let go.
是很难啊
Well, it's hard.
很多妈的东西都回忆起许多美好回忆
A lot of Ma's stuff brings back fond memories.
这就是为什么你一直
Is that why you couldn't get rid of
舍不得清掉她塞满番茄酱的抽屉吗
her drawer full of ketchup packets?
是啊
Yes.
那让我回忆起跟她一起出去吃饭
It reminds me of us eating out and her saying,
她说"快  没人在看  能拿多少包是多少"
"Quick, nobody's looking, fill your pockets with ketchup."
莱纳德
Leonard?
你可曾注意到过
Have you ever noticed
有线台账单上只有我的名字吗
that only my name is on the cable bill?
有啊
Yeah.
很好  那就好
Good, good.
而电费单上只有你的名字
And your name is on the electric bill
而我的不在上面
and mine isn't.
而我也不介意这事
And I'm okay with that.
其实电费单上是你的名字
Actually, your name is on the electric bill.
对哦
Oh, right.
真要命
This is a disaster.
我同意  虽然我都不知道你在说什么
I don't even know what you're talking about and I agree.
好吧  我要跟你说件事
Okay, I have to tell you something,
但你听了一定会不高兴
but you're not going to like it.
怎么了
What's going on?
《科学美国人》上
An article was just published
刊登了一篇关于我们理论的文章
in Scientific American about our theory.
是恶评吗
Did they hate it?
不  是好评
No. No, they loved it.
简直要把我们的理论夸上天了
They, uh, couldn't say enough nice things about it.
那问题到底在哪
So what's the problem?
那你知道购物杂志上只有我的名...
You know how the PennySaver only has my name...
谢尔顿
Sheldon!
文章里没提到你的名字
They didn't mention you in the article.
只提了我
Only me.
真的吗
Really?
我明白
I know.
这样对你很不公平
It's not fair.
让怒火随风而去吧  兄弟
Let the anger go, buddy.
你就...
You just...
你就放松你全身肌肉
you relax all your muscles.
除了你的耻尾肌与肛门括约肌
Except for your pubococcygeus and anal sphincter.
这两条肌你好好绷紧
Let's keep those tight.
不需要这样
Uh, that-that's not necessary.
当然需要  它们帮你止住尿液与粪便呢
It is-- they're what hold back the urine and the feces.
我想你还是不要看比较好
Look, maybe-maybe you shouldn't read it.
看了只会更加不开心
It'll only make you feel worse.
"库珀博士与其团队"
"Cooper and his team"?
我完全不知道他们会这么写
You should know I had nothing to do with that.
至少这文章是关于那理论本身
At least they're talking about the theory.
那才是最重要的
I mean, that's what's important.
没错  你说得对
You know, you're right.
就像当时斯坦·李和史蒂夫·迪特科
Yeah. You know, it's like when Stan Lee and Steve Ditko
创作了蜘蛛侠
created Spider-Man.
或许荣誉全归斯坦·李
Stan Lee may get all the credit,
但史蒂夫·迪特科深知他也同样重要
but Steve Ditko knows he was just as important.
即使斯坦·李客串了所有漫威的超级英雄电影
Even though Stan Lee gets to be in all the Marvel movies.
比史蒂夫有钱得多
And-and he's far richer.
而且他的名字家喻户晓
And he's a household name, you know?
相反  "迪特科"这个名字
Whereas, you know, you say Ditko,
更像是一个做"迪特"的公司
and that sounds like a company that makes Dits.
这话一点帮助都没有
That's not helping.
我本来想多举两个例子
Well, I'd give more examples,
但跟你一样处境的人  名字实在太难记住
but, well, everyone in your position's so forgettable.
斯图尔特  我们到了
Stuart, we're here.
你真好  还让他继续住在你妈妈的房子里
It's nice of you to let him keep staying at your mom's house.
是啊  我试过把他扔在前院马路边送人
Yeah, well, I tried putting him out on the curb,
但没人带走他
but nobody took him.
告诉你们一下  断电了
Just so you know, the power's out.
怎么回事
What happened?
我打电话问了  据说是变压器烧了
I called, they said a transformer blew.
整个街区都没电了
It's the whole block.
应该明天就修好了
Should be fixed by tomorrow.
等等  什么时候没电的
Wait, when did it go out?
昨晚半夜吧
In the middle of the night.
我的老天
Oh, my God.
华仔  怎么了
Howie, what's wrong?
全都解冻了
It's all defrosting.
没关系  只是食物而已
It's okay. It's just food.
不仅仅只是食物
It's not just food.
这是我妈生前做的最后的食物
This is the last food my mother ever made.
这是她最后做的牛胸肉
This is her last brisket.
这是她最后做的肉丸
This is her last meatloaf.
这是她最后做的...
This is her last...
我不知道这是什么  但是...
I have no idea what this is, but...
这也是最后一顿了
it's the last one.
一切还好吗
Everything okay?
不好
No.
所有我妈做的食物要坏掉了
All Ma's food is gonna be ruined.
我们何不把食物都带回家  放进家里冰箱呢
Well, why don't we take it home and put it in our freezer?
你不会想那样做的
You don't want to do that.
二次冷冻不仅会损失水分
Refreezing not only removes moisture,
还会在肉的纤维里产生冰晶
but it creates ice crystals in the fibers of the meat
那会影响肉的味道和肉质
that can compromise its taste and texture.
干嘛  我看见一个施教时刻
What? I saw a teachable moment.
随便教点烹饪学都不行吗
I dropped some culinary science.
那我们该怎么办
What should we do?
我来告诉你我们该怎么做
I'll tell you exactly what we're gonna do.
吃掉它
We're gonna eat it.
这里大概有18斤的食物呢
There's, like, 20 pounds of food in there.
你只是说我得把东西处理掉
All you said was I had to get rid of things.
可你没说它们不能先经过我的结肠啊
You didn't say they couldn't pass through my colon first.
华仔
Howie...
好吧
Okay.
那不如这样
Then how about this?
我们邀请大家来吃晚餐
Let's invite everyone over to dinner.
就像妈最后一次为我们做饭
It'll be like Ma's feeding us one last time.
我喜欢这主意
I love that.
我也是
Me, too.
瞧  我们有这么多番茄酱
Oh, look, we've got enough ketchup
足以覆盖每一寸肉
to cover every ounce of it.
谁会看《科学美国人》这种杂志啊
I mean, who even reads Scientific American?
这本杂志名气挺大的
It's kind of a big deal.
如果它这么有名气  那怎么请来拍封面的
If it's such a big deal, how come the biggest celebrity
超超大牌却是一个小小分子呢
they could get for the cover is a molecule?
我们能不能不说这个话题了
Can we please just stop talking about it?
抱歉  那我能做点什么吗
I'm sorry. What can I do?
不必了  我没事
Nothing, I'm fine.
不不  我要让你开心起来
No, no. I'm gonna cheer you up.
有了
Here we go.
我们要干嘛
What are we doing?
我要带你去购物
I am taking you shopping.
我的宝贝不开心  我要让他开心起来
My baby is sad, and I'm gonna make him happy again.
我知道购物能让你开心
Look, I know shopping cheers you up,
但我对这个真的不感兴趣
but it's just not really my thing.
那这台直升飞机怎么样
Well, what about this helicopter
你可以通过iPad控制哦
you control with an iPad?
里面有摄像头吗
Does it have a camera in it?
里面有摄像头哦
It does have a camera in it.
宝贝表示感兴趣
Baby's listening.
莱纳德
Leonard?
莱纳德  莱纳德
Leonard? Leonard?
干嘛
What?
我跟杂志社的记者谈过了
I spoke to the reporter at the magazine.
然后呢  你告诉他那是我的点子了吗
What happened? Did you tell him it was my idea?
我说了
I did.
谢谢  那他怎么说
Thank you. What did he say?
他说编辑部最终决定
He said they made the editorial decision
只登出主导科学家
to only cite the lead scientist.
他为什么会认为你才是主导科学家
Why did he think you're the lead scientist?
那可是我的点子啊
It was my idea!
对了  多花四块钱
You know, for an extra four bucks,
明天直升机就送到家了哦
I can have this thing here tomorrow.
我知道那是你的点子
Well, I know it was your idea,
但那个记者说他关注我的研究有一段时间了
but the reporter said he's been following my work for a while,
他们杂志刊登那篇文章的唯一理由
and the only reason they even mentioned it in the magazine
就是因为我的名字在上面
is 'cause my name is on it.
算了  我买了  四块钱而已
You know what? I did it. What's four bucks?
如果你的目的是想让我好过点
If you're trying to make me feel better,
你完全没成功
it's not working.
好吧  那如果我告诉你
Well... then what if I told you
我在有线电视账单上加了你的名字呢
that I added your name to the cable bill?
没用
No.
反正也没加上  他们在电话里让我等了20分钟
That's just as well. They had me on hold for 20 minutes
我就挂了  我...
and I hung up. I...
莱纳德  莱纳德
Leonard? Leonard?
莱纳德
Leonard?
沃罗威茨邀请我们一起去吃饭  所以
Also, Wolowitz invited us all to dinner, so...
你准备好了我们就出发
I'm ready whenever you are.
他不就出了个点子吗
All he had was an idea.
点子也是很重要的啊
Well, that is an important part.
拜托
Oh, please!
我脑子里天天都有新点子
I have ideas all day long.
反转海洋公园  里面的海豚可以摸摸人类
Reverse SeaWorld where dolphins are allowed to pet people.
添加一个新尺寸  在中号和大号间加入中大号
A new clothing size between medium and large called Marge.
从小矮人中喷嚏精的角度重述《白雪公主》
Snow White retold from the point of view of Sneezy.
为什么万事通从不给他开药治喷嚏呢
Why won't Doc prescribe him something?
七个小矮人分别叫万事通  害羞鬼  瞌睡虫
喷嚏精  开心果  迷糊鬼  爱生气
我们总算可以知道了
We finally find out.
可莱纳德的点子真的不错啊
But Leonard's idea was good.
那就从爱生气的角度吧  他到底气什么呢
Fine. Then Grumpy-- what's he so grumpy about?
也许是气他女朋友胳膊肘往外拐吧
Maybe his girlfriend won't take his side.
我才是提出点子的那个人
I'm the one who thought of it!
可是很多部分不也都是他完成的吗
Well, didn't he do a lot of the work?
但他现在沉醉于让别人以为
But now he's happy to let people think
一切都是他的功劳
he's responsible for everything.
所以你才能得到平板遥控直升机嘛
And that's why you get an iPad helicopter!
名气比他大难道是我的错吗
Is it my fault I have a much bigger reputation than he does?
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
论文上我的名字按字母顺序排在他前面
Is it my fault that my name came first
这也是我的错吗
on the paper alphabetically?
不是你的错
Not your fault.
记者把我记为主导科学家我没有纠正他
Is it my fault that when the reporter cited me
这也是我的错吗
as the lead scientist I didn't correct him?
快看那只漂亮的小鸟
Hey, look at that pretty bird.
他总是需要成为众人的焦点
He always needs all the attention.
跟个孩子一样
He's such a baby.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
我发誓  我的直升机永远不让他玩
I swear, he is never ever playing with my helicopter.
我要开始加热这些东西了
Okay, I'll start heating some of this stuff up.
谢了
Thanks.
天啊
Oh, man.
这是我高中毕业舞会戴的襟花
This is the boutonniere from my high school prom...
还有我犹太成年礼上剩的一块蛋糕
...A piece of cake from my Bar Mitzvah.
她真是什么都舍不得扔啊
Did she throw anything away?
是啊
No.
要是我的包皮也在里面  我立马自尽
If I find my foreskin, I'm gonna kill myself.
我们现在找到了
Okay, so we've got, um,
3块鸡胸肉  4坨烘肉卷  1份千层面
three briskets, four meatloafs, one lasagna...
不  那是鸡蛋面条
No, that's noodle kugel.
1份犹太千层面
One Jewish lasagna...
2份各重达8磅的磅蛋糕
...two pound cakes that are about eight pounds each,
还有一大盒的面丸子汤
and one giant container of matzah ball soup.
妈妈总是备好丸子汤
Ma always kept it on hand,
以防我生病了
in case I got sick.
她觉得她的菜包治百病
She thought she could cure anything with her cooking.
甚至连食物中毒也能治
Even the time I got food poisoning.
其实就是她的菜害我中毒
From her cooking.
你还好吗
You okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm okay.
我们开始吧
Let's get started.
好的
You got it.
我以后再也没机会和她说话了
I'm never gonna talk to her again.
要不我让大家今天别来了
Should we tell everyone not to come?
不  我想要办这次聚餐
No. I want to do this.
好吧  我们都要坚强点
Okay. Well, I'll keep it together if you can.
好的
Okay.
人家可不保证哦
I'm not making any promises!
你们能来真是太好了
Glad you guys could make it.
一定得来呀
Of course.
这里看起来好漂亮啊
Wow, it looks really pretty in here.
是的  6盏犹太烛台还挺能烘托气氛的
Yeah, turns out half a dozen menorahs really sets a mood.
斯图尔特  如果霍华德卖掉了这房子
So, Stuart, have you thought about what you'd do
你要怎么办呢
if Howard sells the house?
气氛立马灰飞烟灭
And there goes the mood.
嘿  大家好
Hi. Hello.
还要特别向莱纳德问声好
Oh, and a special hello to Leonard,
因为他特别需要被提到名字
who needs to be mentioned by name.
说得好
Subtle.
但你懂我意思  对吧
But you got it, right?
各位
Hey, guys.
我只想让你们知道
I just want everyone to know,
今晚不是一个悲伤的场合
uh, tonight's not a sad occasion.
我们只是想重温一次
Yeah, we just want to have the kind of dinner
大家都在这吃过无数回的晚餐
that we've all had here so many times before.
一桌好菜  一群好友  以及半夜时
Good food, good friends, and sometime around midnight,
令你抓心挠肺的胃灼热感
heartburn that makes you pray for death.
需要去厨房帮你吗
Do you need any help in the kitchen?
不用  你们自己随意就好
No, we got it. You guys make yourselves comfortable.
你俩记住今晚的主角是霍华德好吗
All right, hey, you two, we're here for Howard right now, okay?
对啊  表现乖一点
Yes, so please behave yourselves.
-好吧  -没问题
- Fine. - Of course.
我听说你俩一起写了一篇论文啊
So I heard you two, uh, wrote a paper together.
结果怎么样
How's that going?
这些菜太好吃了
This food is amazing.
而且一点蔬菜也没有
Mm, and not a vegetable in sight.
错了
That's not true.
这里有好多"番茄"呢
We've got tomatoes right here.
一群聪明人围着烛光坐成一圈
All these bright people sitting around a table by candlelight.
感觉仿佛回到了18世纪的法国沙龙
Feels like we could be an 18th century French salon.
没错
Indeed.
佩妮  沙龙是指
Penny, a salon is a gathering
知识分子们围在一起
where intellectuals entertained each other
讨论时下最新的事件
with sparkling conversations about issues of the day.
所以就跟《访谈》节目一样嘛
Oh, so it's like The View.
谢尔顿  《访谈》是一档女性主持的日间节目
Sheldon, The View is a daytime talk show hosted by women.
我知道
Oh, I'm aware.
里面有琥碧·戈博
It features Whoopi Goldberg.
她在《星际迷航·下一代》中扮演了吉南
She played Guinan on Star Trek: Next Gen.
佩妮  《下一代》是指
Penny, Next Gen refers to
-星际迷航的...  -闭嘴
- Star Trek... - Shut up.
我愿意提一个沙龙话题
I would like to propose a salon topic.
愿听其详  拉杰什
Ooh, please do, Rajesh.
《饥饿游戏》的主角是女人
The lead in The Hunger Games is a woman.
漫威也将"托儿"改成了女性
Marvel has made "Tor" a female.
等等  谁是托儿
Wait, who's Tor?
你懂的吧  托儿  "雷神"啊
You know, Tor, the God of "Tunder."
综上所述  这是标志着
As I was saying, is this a sign
我们的社会逐步走向性别平等
that our society is approaching gender equality?
现在很多女性也爱看漫画了
Certainly a lot more women are reading comic books now.
这是真的
It's true.
我还得为店里厕所装上个马桶坐垫
At the store, I had to put a seat on the toilet.
在女索尔生孩子后
We won't know if there's equality
而其他复仇者们不介意
until female Thor has a baby
她在工作场所挤母乳之前  性别平等还很难说
and the Avengers are cool with her pumping breast milk at work.
我在想什么样的孩子才有资格
I wonder if only a baby who is worthy
能吸雷神的奶子
can suckle at the bosom of Thor.
新沙龙话题
Okay, new salon topic.
沙龙  是从很久以前就这么蠢
Salons-- dumb thing from a long time ago
还是本来挺好的  讨论起超级英雄才变蠢的
or interesting thing made dumb by talking about superheroes?
讨论开始
Discuss.
我觉得沙龙的话题并不重要
I don't believe it matters what the topic is.
沙龙重要的是
What's crucial for a salon
我们可以将讨论
is that we conduct the discussion
变得生动且有见解
in an elevated and insightful way.
重点在于如何执行
It's all about the execution.
你当然注重执行  而不是注重灵感
Of course you'd focus on that rather than the inspiration.
新沙龙话题
Uh, new salon topic.
点子和执行力哪个更为重要
What's more important, an idea or its execution?
这个好
Oh, that's fun.
说得不错  莱纳德
Yeah, good for you, Leonard.
这个观点很有趣
That's a lovely little notion.
就好比
Kind of like,
"我非常想跟我在芝加哥的舅舅通话"
"I wish I could talk to my uncle in Chicago."
行  先闪边  我发明电话去
Yeah, now stand back while I invent the telephone.
"您好  请稍等"
"Hello? Oh, hold on."
莱纳德  是你舅
Leonard, it's your uncle.
他说你炸了
He says you just got burned.
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
你们俩
You guys.
没事
No, it's okay.
我们都是成人  正在进行知识上的探讨
We're all adults trying to have an intelligent discussion.
至少我是这样
At least I am.
霍华德你觉得呢
Howard, what do you think?
我作为一名工程师
Well, I guess, as an engineer,
我的答案倾向于执行
lean towards execution.
我的工作就是将点子
I spend my days trying to take
变成为真实的东西
ideas and make them real.
说的好  老兄
Well said, old chap.
谁说世人再无雄辩  我们面前不就是吗
I thought eloquence had died; here it stands before us.
从今天开始  刚才那段话与葛底斯堡演说
Starting today, it'll go: Gettysburg Address,
葛底斯堡演说是美国林肯总统最伟大与著名的演说
《我有一个梦想》则是马丁·路德·金最著名的一场演说
还有《我有一个梦想》齐名
"I have a dream" and what you just said.
现在他就是天才啦
Oh, now he's a genius?
你以前不是一直嘲笑他是工程师吗
All you ever do is make fun of him and engineering.
莱纳德  注意点  人家才刚刚丧母
Leonard, please. His mother just died.
你真是要笑死人
You're being ridiculous.
你也是
Yeah, so are you.
同志们  如果要听撕逼
Guys, if I wanted to hear people be bitchy,
我就去我的美发沙龙了
I'd go to my real salon.
莱纳德  很多人都可以有过那点子
Leonard, lots of people could've had that idea,
但只有少数人能像我一样去实现它
but very few people could've worked out the math the way I did.
还有很多人提不出这样的点子呢
Lots of people also didn't have that idea,
比如除了我以外的全世界
like everyone in the entire world except for me.
看来莱纳德觉得自己
Oh, well, apparently Leonard thinks
比全世界所有人都强
he's better than everyone in the whole world,
包括为我们的自由而战的人们
including those fighting for our freedom.
我不知道你怎么想的
Yeah, well, I don't know about you,
但我支持我国在海外的英雄们
but I support our boys overseas.
还有英雌们
And girls.
你已经把雷神毁了  歇会吧你
Hey, you already ruined Thor; give it a rest.
所以我就活该忍受
So I'm just supposed to be okay
你把功劳都霸占了
with you hogging all the credit?!
我什么都没霸占
I didn't hog anything.
不像你  霸占着那坨有葡萄干的千层面
Unlike you and that weird lasagna with raisins in it.
你想要吗
You want some of this?
我赏你一顿饱啊
I'll give you some.
谢尔顿  莱纳德  马上给我去客厅
Sheldon, Leonard, living room, right now!
她先叫的我  你嫉妒死了吧
She said my name first; that must kill you.
我不知道你俩是要闹哪样
I don't know what you think you're doing,
但我老公现在可是很难过
but this is a very difficult time for my husband!
我们吃的是他老妈最后做的食物
We're eating the last food his mother ever made,
你们俩还想学熊孩子  把饭拿起来乱扔吗
and you were gonna throw it at each other like children?!
不管你俩吵什么玩意  给我憋回去
Whatever it is you're fighting about, put it aside,
滚回桌子乖乖当好霍华德的朋友
go back in there and be a good friend to Howard
不然甜点没你俩的份
or there's no dessert for either of you!
我在跟你们说话呢  看着我
Look at me when I'm talking to you!
别想...
And don't think...
你们注意到
You guys ever notice sometimes
有时候博纳黛特和我妈说话有点像吗
Bernadette sounds like my mom?
没听出来啊
I don't hear it.
哪有  完全没有
No, not at all.
我这辈子没吃过这么撑
I don't think I've eaten that much in my entire life.
所以我们族人在沙漠里暴走了四十年
It's why my people wandered the desert for 40 years.
犹太人祖先出走埃及后
曾在沙漠度过40年的漂泊帐篷生活
才能把肚子里的东西消化掉
Took that long to walk it off.
佩妮  是这样的  以色列人在沙漠中...
You see, Penny, the Israelites were in the desert...
闭嘴
Shut up!
太高兴你俩不吵了
So glad you two are done fighting.
现在我只想怎么把嗝打出来才不会吐
Right now, I'm just trying to burp without throwing up.
等等
Hang on.
《今日物理》提到了我们的论文
Physics Today mentioned the paper.
他们怎么说
What'd they say?
谁在乎  他们提莱纳德了吗
Who cares? Did they mention Leonard?
提到了
They did.
太好了
Yay.
好消息  我又找到抗胃酸片了
Good news, I found more Tums.
太好了
Yay!